Bobby.
No!
All right. we lined up?
Get that line.
Put the stern line on quick.
Bobby!
Hey. baby!
Missed you.
Hey. big man. how you doing?
- Hey. Murph!
- Hey. Ethel.
How you doing? Welcome home.
- You seen Deb and my boy?
- No. I'm sorry.
Ma!
- How you doing. beautiful?
- Hello. Bobby.
Home safe.
Who's that?
- OI' Ben.
- No.
Poor old guy.
Hey. Linda.
- Hey. boss.
- What's the score?
My kind of numbers.
I lost Ben Pulley.
He passed away onboard.
Sorry to hear that.
How'd you hit it. Billy?
Didn't hit very hard. did you?
We all have slumps. but you're overdue
to break out of yours.
Did you hear the lady?
Ben Pulley's dead.
That old man pickled himself to death
drinking 7& 7s chasing Narragansetts.
Linda. with Ben. it was never
a question of "if." but "when."
- I'll bury him.
- I'll pay for it.
See. you got what you wanted.
Bring in your fish.
It shouldn't take too long.
8-5.
4-7-5.
Murph.
Sign my ledger.
Shatford.
What's the matter?
It's $2221.
Aren't we a little short?
We were sharing up last night.
I thought it'd be three plus.
You stocked 21.000 pounds at 3.50
a pound. That comes to $ 73.000.
Minus $35.000 for bait. tackle. fuel.
That comes out to $38.500.
I get half. I own the boat.
Your captain takes double share.
four crewmen get a share each.
And a rookie like you.
three-quarters share.
That comes to $2221.
What it is. is what it is.
Sign the ledger.
Moran.
You going out again this season.
skipper?
Why?
You got a site in Florida?
Bradenton Beach.
The Cecile.
Pack your shit and get out.
You like Florida?
Well. it beats the Grand Banks
in October.
It gets rough up here.
Dougie likes the sun down there.
Or he thinks he'll score better
with another captain.
I didn't say that.
Yes. you did.
Goodbye.
Here's your cut. $5923.76.
Sign the ledger.
That's a record low for you.
isn't it?
Next time. track Linda.
She'll take you where the fish are.
You're getting to be rude. you know?
I like you. Billy.
I always have.
But I like my boat better.
If you can't make it pay.
I'll find somebody who can.
You trying to put a charge up my ass?
You're on a cold streak.
I'm encouraging you
to catch fish.
I'll bring you more fish
than you ever dreamed of.
Next time I fish the Grand Banks.
they won't be so grand.
You just struck out
on the Grand Banks.
Then I'll go further.
Don't even think about it.
I want my boat back.
And I want to catch some fish.
It's what I do.
Not lately.
Want to yank my site. you go ahead.
- Murph.
- Hey. skip.
What are you doing out here?
Get in there. Get drunk.
Waiting on my ex...
...and my son.
Give him lots of
hugs and kisses tonight.
You don't gotta remind me
to do that. skip.
Ladies. you're looking fine.
How you doing?
Can I buy you a drink?
What. what. what?
Hey. rookie.
What are you so happy about?
It wasn't exactly a slammer
up on the Grand Banks.
Isn't it past your bedtime?
Bugs. how you making out?
I'm not.
I don't know.
Maybe I smell like fish.
- You need a new deodorant.
- Maybe I need a new face.
Frickin' Alfred Pierre.
They were upstairs. they come down.
a little refreshment.
Now they're going back up again.
Half an hour ago. they shook
the lamps over the bar.
Last time she brought her sister.
You should've seen the lamps then.
How do he do it. mon?
I think he's fishin'
with a longer pole. Bugs.
What happened?
They had a sale on kids' shoes
at Ames.
Sorry.
No problem.
Hi.
Hello.
So you want to have a drink?
Come on. Debra.
What do you say. for old times' sake?
It was the old times that killed us.
Is that what it was?
There you go.
I'm a little short.
It wasn't exactly a slammer.
Half for you.
You sure?
Yeah. I'm working.
Want to come with your daddy?
Shoot some pool?
Have a drink?
Just bring him home in an hour.
Good shot. buddy.
All right. Sully. you think about it.
All right?
Bugs.
Murph. come here.
Here comes your fearless leader.
Captain Billy Tyne.
I got a feeling skipper's
coming to give us bad news.
Lady's not only pretty. she's smart.
Yeah. we're going back out.
What'd I tell you?
- When?
- A few days.
"Few" means two?
Two days is right.
Skip. we just got back in.
You don't want your site.
a replacement's a call away.
Join me. don't join me.
There's time for one last shot.
The Andrea Gail will take it.
This time I promise you. we'll
come back with a shitload of fish.
Excuse me. men. madam.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna tell him to
stick his head up his ass.
I'd like to hear that.
Hear what?
I'd like to hear you tell him
to stick it up his ass.
Go on. Bob.
Yeah. that's just how I'll tell him
as soon as we get back.
You're a bastard.
Why? Why do I even love you?
- Come on.
- No. Why? Why. Bobby?
When you get the answer. tell me.
I could use it myself.
- Get laid. Bugsy.
- Easy for you to say.
Go on up there.
Don't make the same mistake I did.
You're going away again?
Yeah.
Take me with you.
Come here.
Go back. Bobby.
Go back to what you did before.
- Pack cod. repair tackle.
- I'm sick of that.
It's safe and it pays.
Not enough.
Just one more time. I promise.
I have to try it again.
We need the money. baby.
Money. It's always about the money.
Well. I got a divorce lawyer.
a mountain of debt.
And there's your two kids.
You gotta get them back.
Do you think you'll love them?
They're yours. aren't they?
Hey. beautiful.
Yeah. you.
Buy you a drink?
Seeing as I got two in front of me.
I don't think so.
I'm not very observant. am I?
I got a feeling. yeah.
along with a lot of other things.
Why don't we start over?
You know what would look good on you?
Me.
No good?
Have a drink. It's not that bad.
Thank you. Here's to crime.
You're pathetic.
You still want to be a fisherman?
Who told you I wanted to be
a fisherman?
You want to come with me.
I want to come with you.
but I don't want to be a fisherman.
You know. buddy...
...one of these days your mom's
gonna find you a new dad.
I don't want a new dad.
I'm sorry.
Your mom can't sit around
by herself all the time.
She isn't sitting around.
I'm sure he's a good guy.
I know your mom wouldn't take up
with anybody but a good guy.
And you know. buddy...
...the most important thing is
that you and Mommy are happy.
Can we talk about something else now?
I miss you too. buddy.
I miss you so damn much.
What'd you say your name was again?
Irene. Is that so tough?
I'm sorry. Listen.
Could I maybe take you home?
I don't think so.
I came to watch the game. Instead I
got schnockered with Bugsy.
- What does Bugsy stand for anyway?
- Michael.
That's a nice name.
Why don't you use it?
Because people know me as Bugsy.
I'm gonna shove off now.
Big day tomorrow.
I can't take you home?
What. in a wheelbarrow?
Crew guys like you never have cars.
Lay off. I got feelings too.
Where. down in your pants?
Jesus. lady. where's the passion
in your life?
Home in bed.
One of them's 6. the other one's 8.
All I can say is.
there's some lucky kids.
They got a wonderful mother.
You're not messing with me. are you?
Haven't got time.
We're going out in two days.
Well. I'm sorry to hear that. Michael.
Gotta go.
What do you mean?
- Where you going?
- Have these.
- Thank you.
- See you.
- Bye. Ethel.
Watch your step.
I smell Coppertone.
That means that
Captain Linda Greenlaw...
...a lady vain about her nose.
is in my wheelhouse.
Make that Hawaiian Tropic.
At least I got the nose right.
Your guys are loading bait
and groceries.
- You doing a turnaround?
- No rest for the weary.
There you go.
Flaunting your work ethic.
I don't have a work ethic.
I just have work.
If I'm gonna catch up to you.
I love to watch you study charts.
Why?
You know them all by heart.
What's special about today
that you're blowing smoke up my ass?
I thought I'd make a pass.
You see. I'm looking for a guy
to come home to Maine with me...
...buy a house and raise kids.
What does that guy and you do after?
The thing is. I'm happy.
I'm happy I'm fit to do this.
I just don't see the romance in it.
But you've got it. Captain Greenlaw.
You do. Believe me.
I've seen them come and go.
The day I laid eyes on you. I said.
"She's gonna be a good one."
You can't be good unless you love it.
The fog's just lifting.
You throw off your bow line.
throw off your stern.
You head out the South Channel...
...past Rocky Neck.
Ten Pound Island...
...past Niles Pond.
where I skated as a kid.
Blow your horn...
...and wave to the lighthouse
keeper's kid on Thatcher Island.
Then the birds show up.
Black-backs...
...herring gulls. big dump ducks.
The sun hits you.
Head north. open up to 12.
You're steaming now.
The guys are busy.
you're in charge.
You know what?
You're a goddamn swordboat captain.
Is there anything better in the world?
Sully.
So what do you think?
You been busy?
Busy enough.
I was working menhaden in Annisquam.
But they laid off Labor Day.
Mended nets over in Fairhaven.
That's crap.
What's this you're doing now?
Helping out a friend.
He paying you?
He's my friend.
Murphy keep his site?
You want this job or not?
I do.
Lord. did I do that?
Yeah. you did.
But I'm not completely blind.
I can still see out of the other one.
Next time I should break a leg.
Then you can stay home
and collect disability.
Think of all those
handicapped parking spaces.
Tell me last night was worth it.
I can't remember.
Can't remember. my ass.
No. I remember your ass.
Last night was worth it.
There's nothing like
sleeping with you.
Just sleeping...
...lying next to you...
...all warm and sweet.
And me wishing the morning
would never come.
Catching up.
Oh. boy. oh. boy.
Look at that shiner.
Come on. Murph. will you?
Good morning.
Where'd you get the mouse?
Chris "Boom-Boom" Cotter.
Put some hair around that hole.
I bet you could hit it.
Not with a pool cue.
or any other pointed instrument.
What do you know except to cut squid
and take them to bed with you?
Ethel. where you getting
your customers these days?
The welfare office?
Who gave you that scar. tough guy?
Back off! Back off.
Come on. swing it.
You assholes!
How you gonna act onboard if you're
already at each other's throats?
All right. Ma.
See you onboard.
- Alfred Pierre. one for the road?
- No. tanks. Mom.
"No. tanks. Mom."
Guy can't even speak good English.
Well. anyway. can I get you anything?
Let's go. boys.
I'll wait for you in the car. Bobby.
Catch fish. boys. Lots of them.
Full ahead.
Hold down the fort. Quentin.
Thanks. Q.
Thanks. Ethel.
Gotta go. Mom.
The Grand Banks.
I know.
Grand Banks are no joke in October.
All right?
Be careful.
At least we'll get cancer together.
I can't put it off any longer.
I'm not too big on goodbyes.
Don't go. Bobby. I got a bad feeling.
I've been thinking about it.
Then for God's sake. don't go.
I'll moonlight. I'll sell the car.
We'll work nights. weekends.
Whatever it takes. little by little.
we'll put something away.
I gotta go.
Michael.
Irene.
Irene. I knew that.
I just wanted to say goodbye.
No one ever said goodbye to me before.
Well. goodbye. Irene.
Goodbye.
I wish it were night so I could say.
"Good night. Irene."
That'll come later.
Well. you gotta go.
Come on. boys. Let's go.
I love you.
I will always love you. Christina.
Pack it in there good.
We got more coming down.
Did we get all them eggs up there?
We catching some fish
Is that gonna crap out again?
Never!
Do you mind?
Stinks in here. doesn't it?
Not anymore.
Hi. Bobby:
You're somewhere out there...
... on the deep blue. goddamn sea...
... and I'm writing this on a box
of two semi-down pillows...
... that I secretly bought for us
at Penney's.
And I'm smiling to myself because...
... of the surprise I have
in store for you.
I'm talking removal from our dungeon
in the Crow's Nest...
... to our own place.
It's no great shakes...
... but you gotta begin
with a baby shake. right?
Forever love. Bobby.
I'm in this for the long run.
- I'm not intruding. am I?
- You're not intruding.
You're a natural.
You've got some old salt
in your blood.
Thanks.
You're a happy man out here.
aren't you?
Today. maybe.
When do you get unhappy?
The day we go home.
Home? I thought the sea
was your home.
You got me there.
But if you were gonna pin me down...
...I guess Pensacola. Florida is home.
My ex lives there. Jodi.
And my kids.
I wasn't very good at doing things
the way they're supposed to be done.
Wife.
Kids.
A house with things in it.
All that stuff.
So why are you so happy?
You just got me on a good day.
I'm doing what I was made to do.
And I got a feeling I'll do it
even better this time.
How about you?
I got a woman I can't stand to be
more than two feet away from.
Congratulations.
Then again. I love to fish.
Son. you've got a problem.
I know.
Here you are.
What do you think? Blue skies.
scattered showers. same old. same old?
- Your guess is as good as mine.
- Or better.
Watch it.
This doesn't look good.
Looks pretty ugly here too.
Pam.
Tell Bernie I need two graphics:
Bermuda and Sable Island.
Good.
What's our course?
I've been sailing 42 years.
Never plotted a course.
I set the compass. I ride it...
...we'll be in Bermuda in no time.
Let's go fishing.
All right. guys. let's hit it!
1000 hooks in the water before dinner.
I want 40 miles out there.
Three-mile buoy out!
Yeah. baby.
Set.
Okay. Sully. put it out.
Highflyer!
Hey. A.P.
May the force be with us.
You want to play with lightsticks.
stick them up your ass.
Easy. Murph.
He's dead weight.
He's been screwing around all night.
A juicer and a head.
Cape Ann. bottom shelf.
Yeah. well. your wife
didn't feel that way.
Hey. knock it off!
I'll head for land and the Newfies
will throw you both in jail!
All right. cap.
Give us some lights.
Come on. Jesus.
Shake. you guys.
Shake!
- Just let it go.
- Your day is coming.
Whenever you're ready.
I'll be right up here.
The job ain't hard enough
without this knucklehead.
Let's go.
We're gonna make some money.
Let's go. boys!
Let's go! Come on!
Come on.
Do it. skip. do it.
Make a killing.
One's on.
Fish on.
Have those gaffs ready.
Don't lose him. Murph.
Don't lose him.
Pull him in. Murph.
All right. now. gaff him. Gaff him!
One. two. three!
Pull him in.
Come on. a little bit more.
So what do you think?
Do you think he'll like it?
He'll love it.
Enough to live with me in it?
By now. honey. you know him
much better than I do.
We're gonna make a go of it.
I got confidence in you.
What. are you putting me on?
He's my precious boy.
And you're the woman for him.
That's something I don't joke about.
The activity down near Bermuda
is deepening rapidly.
Given the warm and volatile
Gulf Stream...
... it won't take much to turn
this tropical storm into a hurricane.
This just in. video of Sable Island.
I put so much ground beef and sausage
in this. it weighed out at 20 pounds.
More than most of our fish weigh.
Skipper say anything about us
coming up short?
He's too scared to say.
Skipper don't get scared.
Just disappointed.
You know why this lasagna weighs
20 pounds?
It tasted like you
threw in a shot put.
I once worked a site
with a guy like you.
The guy had a real bad accident.
Can't even keep track of them
with so many accidents at sea.
Tough to get an ambulance too.
Keep it up.
Highflyer!
A.P.. give me a hand.
Hey. how about a little hand
over here?
You do your job. I'll do mine.
Come on. guys.
Came out here for nothing.
Keep moving. keep moving.
Come on. Sully. let's get
some bait going here.
It's big.
- Something very big.
- Fish on!
Come on. guys.
Oh. yeah.
Come on. Bring it up.
Bring it up.
Get the gaff!
Get it out of here!
Stick him.
Stick it in his head! Good!
Get him off!
- He's got my leg!
- Hang on!
Kick your foot out! Kick it!
Kick your foot out.
Get back!
All right. come on. get it out!
Get it out of here.
- Pull him back!
- Over the side.
You all right?
You're short a boot. rookie!
Beats a leg. don't it?
Okay. we're getting a reading of winds
over 140 knots sustained.
Looks like a category 5.
"Billy Tyne is no fine wine
He's lost his touch with our long line
Steamed here and there and all about
What's our tally?
We've struck out"
All right. okay.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Why aren't you downstairs
watching the movie?
One of our three movies?
I know them all by heart.
Skip...
...what are you gonna do
about those sets? They suck.
We ain't doing nothing.
The boys been talking?
About how I lost it?
Billy Tyne's lost it? Gets a little
slow. they'll draw and quarter you.
I just didn't think
you'd go along with it.
I come here because I need the money.
I'm trying for a new start.
Last trip I thought you had
something to offer.
But all in all.
you're just a little punk.
- You promised me a shitload of fish!
- You'll get a shitload of fish.
I've been in bad patches so many times
and came home with so much stock...
...little boys like you had to
pack it on the pier.
I always find the fish! Always!
And I will this time!
So don't fuck with me!
Aye. aye. skip.
Put them closer!
Murph. closer!
Give them a goddamn banquet.
Aye. aye. cap.
You heard him. boys.
Boss ain't happy.
Double-time.
Let's go. Bob.
Sullivan!
I gotta hit you with a fish again
to get you to work?
Lightsticks. now!
Shut up. asshole!
You couldn't bait fish in a barrel!
- Come on.
- See what I got to deal with?
That's a landlubber.
What an idiot!
Come on. Sully.
What are you. a fisherman or a farmer?
Bugs. help him out.
Hurry up. before the captain sees.
Okay. sure. I'll help him out.
What a screwup!
- You're useless. Sully!
- Lay off. Bugs. You never screw up?
You're nothing but a pimple
on the ass of progress.
I've been on a better slab than this.
I've had it with this.
Take it easy.
It was an accident.
You got the easiest job on the boat.
and you manage to screw it up!
Kiss my ass. you little runt.
And you...!
Murph!
Cap. man overboard!
Take the wheel!
Back her down slow.